Alan Justino da Silva

Senior Software Engineer

São Caetano do Sul, São Paulo, Brazil

☑ alan.justino@yahoo.com.br ☐ +55 (11) 998-225-769

in alanjustino alanjds alanjds alanjds

I am a Software Engineer experienced with Python and skills on the full stack & machine learning. Coding commercial Python since 2008, right after leading a team to create a XEN cloud. When allowed, I target to build software and infra made to scale.

Now, I do what is needed from cloud-or-not DevOps to intermediate HTML/CSS/JS coding, mainly using

Postgres+Redis and Django or Flask on the backend, although preferring async options.

Some time ago I got to work with machine learning tech and published a paper at an international conference.

I try to merge back my bugfixes when possible. In fact, contributed code to many useful projects like Celery, Cassandra, Ansible, DRF, Kivy & RustPython among others, and created the drf-nested-router package.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

LIKES:

Python Django PostgreSQL

Linux 12Factor Apps Machine Learning

FaaS Redis Cassandra

RabbitMQ ElasticSearch Kafka

HTML/CSS/JS Rust Celery

Agile Management Teamwork Docker

WebAssembly GraphQL RESTful APIs

DISLIKES:

VB6

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dec 2019 - Current

Senior Software Engineer at PolySwarm

San Juan, Puerto Rico (remote) http://polyswarm.io

PostgreSQL ElasticSearch Kafka K8s AWS Ethereum Python Typescript Node.JS Clickhouse ML Wine

Slack API

Digital Security platform with a distributed antivirus aggregator that yields cripto to the antivirus authors.

- Rework or refactor of existing systems to provide the scalability needed for the business growth.
- Integrate with BitGo custodian, assuring safety & idempotency for no double-spending
- Maintenance of internal ML models and tools
- Filled gaps that made possible to list our coin NCT on Coinbase

Jul 2009 - Current

training management agile scrum kanban scrapping AWS Python Django Docker GIT Foundation-Zurb

Consulting and custom software development. Mainly web apps. Heroku, AWS or locally hosted.

- Training small teams during internal technology changes
- Temporarily managing small startup teams when the CTO burned out

Mar 2017 - Dec 2019

Senior Python Engineer at GetNinjas

São Paulo, SP, Brazil (hybrid) Thttps://www.getninjas.com.br/



The upcoming Data Science squad needed an experienced Software Engineer with academic research skills, that can talk and understand the Data Scientists needs and transfer this to business and tech decisions.

Jun 2015 - Feb 2017

Senior Python Developer at BooLabs, then B2W

São Paulo, SP, Brazil (hybrid) Lhttps://br.linkedin.com/company/b2w---companhia-global-do-varejo

ML visual recognition bigdata ecommerce Cassandra ElasticSearch RabbitMQ Kafka Ansible Scala training

Deep-learning and visual recognition AI shop. BooLabs developed AI products targeting retail sales market. I received ML training from a founder, PhD in Machine Learning.

Dec 2014 - Jun 2015

Tech Lead at Omelete Group

São Paulo, SP, Brazil https://www.omelete.com.br/

Python Django PostgreSQL Redis ElasticSearch uwsgi management Foundation-Zurb

Geek hardnews with 3k pages per minute of server-side pressure after a Varnish cache.

I hired, trained and lead the team that rearchitectured and implemented the full stack solution.

Nov 2012 - Jan 2013

Specialist Teacher at SENAC (Commerce' Guild Social Service)

Santo André, São Paulo, Brazil thttps://www.sp.senac.br/

training SQL

Teaching data modeling with relational databases and SQL. Teaching backend languages for the web.

(Disclaimer: Senac's contract model is of 3 months per venture, then quarantine)

Mar 2012 - Nov 2012

Software Engineer at Pitzi

São Paulo, SP, Brazil https://www.pitzi.com.br/

UX Ruby-on-Rails 12Factor App PostgreSQL Redis

Growing Ruby on Rails software with the startup that brings the first Club of Service for Mobile in Brazil. Part of the founder team.

Jan 2011 - Mar 2012

Software Developer at Rede Colibri

🗣 São Paulo, SP, Brazil

Python Django Celery PostgreSQL WebSockets Linux AWS

Real Estate startup. Brings the MLS model to Brazil in a way that brazilian brokers can enjoy and profit.

May 2006 - Jul 2009

Computer Technician, then Infrastructure Lead at Universidade Federal do ABC - UFABC

Santo André, São Paulo, Brazil L'https://www.ufabc.edu.br/

management cloud infra Linux VoIP

Leader of the Network Infrastructure Team, in direct relationship with 1st and 2nd management levels, leading up to 10 team members distributed among 4 sites.

EDUCATION (2)

2006 - 2009

Bachelor of Information Technology Systems at Universidade de São Paulo - USP

Software Engineering Project Management Machine Learning User Experience

2003 - 2004

Tech High School with Data Processing at Escola Técnica Estadual "Lauro Gomes" - ETELG

C++ Python

CERTIFICATES

LPIC-1

Linux Professional Institute

PUBLICATIONS

3 Oct 2017

Go vs CPython: Visual comparison of concurrency and parallelism options in labs.getninjas.com.br

13 Jul 2016

BooViews: Aspect-based Sentiment Analysis on Product Reviews combining SVM and CRF in Portuguese in PROPOR 2016 - International Conference on the Computational Processing of Portuguese

LANGUAGES

English
Fluent

Portuguese

Native Speaker

Italian

Intermediate

TOOLS

first computer

486 DX2 66

favorite editor

VSCodium w/ vim emulation

current book

30-Second Archtecture (Edward Denison)